# Ufonabasi Umo

Nigeria



ufonumo@gmail.com



07013504471



linkedin.com/in/ufonabasi-umo-879271160

## **Summary**

I am a front-end developer with more than two years of experience designing and developing responsive web designs and mobile apps in a variety of industries, including health care, food, and agriculture. With a strong understanding of UX and user psychology, I'm an expert in CSS and JS frameworks. Among the notable accomplishments is increasing the conversion rate of an existing website by 80% with enhanced code and design.

## **Experience**

## **Gube** Frontend Developer

iQube Labs

Nov 2021 - Present (7 months +)

- Worked on a web application that allowed patients to easily schedule an appointment with a doctor by entering their symptoms, length of illness, and type of illness, as well as selecting a payment subscription plan. By caching the webpages, I was able to reduce the time it took to load the application by 70%.
- As a web team liaison for all inter-departmental and customer-facing initiatives, I implemented web apps and 3rd-party software integrations.
- Collaborated with the PM to keep the project plan, timeline, and billing on track. This saved an average of four days of communication per project.
- Maintained and developed a web application that makes it possible for several users to watch cuisine videos and participate in live classes based on their subscription plan.
- Collaborated with Quality Assurance to test new pages/products and respond to any issues within 48 hours.
- Created a secure login for over 100 users and implemented the user interface for a database of customer health applications.

#### √ Frontend mentor

Reskill Americans

Sep 2021 - Oct 2021 (2 months)

- Responsible for providing individualized assistance to over 20 students in order to assist them in understanding new ideas and completing projects
- Assisted 20 students understand key concepts in frontend programming languages like React and JavaScript.

## Frontend Developer

Cecula Ltd.

Sep 2020 - Feb 2021 (6 months)

- Implemented a web application that allows close to 100 food merchants to simply create meal menus, bundles, and other goods for customers to purchase.

- Built a website for a variety of businesses that enables job seekers to apply for opportunities from the comfort of their own homes.

## Frontend Web Developer

**HNG Internship** 

Sep 2019 - Nov 2019 (3 months)

- Developed an e-commerce website where customers can purchase African-inspired dresses, jumpsuits, and other accessories.
- Created the website's user interface with Material Ui and used Commerce JavaScript with the Chec API as the backend for all of the store's products.
- Utilized react functional components to design the application's structure and passed props between all of the components, as well as react-router-dom to connect them. Stripe was also used to accept payments on the platform.

### **Education**



### Bells University of Technology

Bachelor of Technology - B.Tech, Surveying and Geoinformatics 2016 - Aug 2021

#### **Licenses & Certifications**

- HNG internship HNG Internship
- **Google Developer Student Clubs lead** Google
- Jobberman Soft-Skills Training Jobberman Nigeria

#### Skills

React.js • JavaScript • TypeScript • Next js • HTML5 • SASS • Bootstrap • Cascading Style Sheets (CSS) • ArcGIS Explorer • Argisoft